Start spreading the newspaper.
The Wild is a family, animation film directed by Steve Williams.
An adolescent lion is accidentally shipped from the New York Zoo to Africa.
Now running free, his zoo pals must put aside their
differences to help bring him back.
Samson (voice), played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Benny (voice), played by Jim Belushi.
Nigel (voice), played by Eddie Izzard.
Bridget (voice), played by Janeane Garofalo.
Kazar (voice), played by William Shatner.
Larry (voice), played by Richard Kind.
The Wild is a 2006 animated adventure comedy film directed by Steve
"Spaz" Williams with a screenplay by Ed Decter, John J.
Strauss, Mark Gibson and Philip Halprin, and featuring the voices of  Kiefer Sutherland, Eddie Izzard, Jim
Belushi, Janeane Garofalo, Richard Kind, Greg Cipes, Patrick Warburton and William Shatner.
The film's plot centers around Samson, a male lion who loses his pre-teen son, Ryan, who wanders off and accidentally gets shipped from the
Central Park Zoo to Africa, leading his father to team up with a group of animals as they embark on a journey to save his lost son.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures, Hoytyboy Pictures, Sir
Zip Studios, Contrafilm, and C.O.R.E.
Feature Animation, The Wild was animated by C.O.R.E.
Digital Pictures, and released by Buena Vista Pictures
Distribution in North America on April 14, 2006.
The film earned $102 million on an $80 million
budget, making it a commercial failure.
Reviews were largely negative, with many critics comparing it unfavorably to
Madagascar (2005), Finding Nemo (2003), and The Lion King (1994).
It was the only film produced by C.O.R.E before they shut down in 2010.
The film explores themes of new york city, africa, lion, zoo.